(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-01T01:19:02.945680",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
はい、尾丸ポルカです！よろしくお願いします！
Hi, I'm Omaru Polka! Nice to meet you!
こんばんは！ホロライブの白上フブキです。よろしくお願いします！
Good evening! I'm Shirakami Fubuki from Hololive. Nice to meet you!
さて、今夜も始まりました「ミュージックガーデン」でございますけどもー
Now then, tonight's "Music Garden" has also begun, but...
なんか、久しぶりだね。
It's been a while, huh.
はい、約2年ぶりに復活…
Yes, coming back after about two years...
ということでですね
So, with that being said,
復活、おめでとう！
Congratulations on your comeback!
そうですね！
That's right!
あ、切ってないですけども
Ah, I haven't cut my hair though.
２年目もそんなこと言ってましたね
You were saying the same thing in your second year.
そうだっけ！？
Was I!?
そうですよ！ポルちゃんお変わりなく。
That's right! Polka, you never change.
ま、はい、元気でやってます。
Well, yeah, I'm doing well.
それはよかったです！ポルちゃんの元気には負けないくらい。
That's good! We're not going to lose to Polka's energy.
今回元気なゲストさんもいますので。
We have some very energetic guests this time too.
うーん、それは楽しみだね！
Hmm, I'm looking forward to that!
はい、では早速紹介していきましょうか。本日のゲストの登場です！
Now then, let's introduce them right away. Here come today's guests!
音乃瀬奏
Otonose Kanade
猫又おかゆ
Nekomata Okayu
大神ミオ
Ookami Mio
百鬼あやめ
Nakiri Ayame
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
今夜も豪華ゲストでお送りするミュージックガーデン！
Tonight's Music Garden features a gorgeous lineup of guests!
なんと今夜は、あっ！と驚くような仕掛けいっぱいででお送りするみたいですよ！
And tonight, it seems we'll be delivering tons of surprising gimmicks!
最後まで見逃せません！
You won't want to miss a single moment until the end!
ああー、どんな仕掛けなんだろうねぇ…
Ah, I wonder what kind of gimmicks they are...
えー、鷹嶺ルイくん。
Uh, Takane Lui-kun.
はい。ミュージックガーデンといえば、ま、鷹嶺ルイくんだから。今日は誕生日ということでで
Yes. Speaking of Music Garden, well, it's Takane Lui-kun's birthday today, so—
はい、ありがとうございます。そうなんですよ。今日誕生日なんですよ。
Yes, thank you very much. That's right, today is my birthday.
まぁ、何年ぶりに復活したけど、ど、緊張してる？
Well, I made a comeback after several years, but a-are you nervous?
はい。緊張してます。でも復活にふさわしい場にできるんじゃないかなと思っているので、楽しみにしていてください。
Yes, I'm nervous. But I'm hoping to make it a fitting place for my comeback, so please look forward to it.
復活…、これなんか匂いますね？
Comeback... I smell something here?
え？あ、ちゃんと風呂に入ってきた。いや、その匂いじゃなくて、違いますね、それじゃないですよ。
Eh? Ah, I took a bath properly. No, not that smell, that's not it.
あ、そっかそっか。
Ah, I see, I see.
今日は1曲目が披露だよね？
Today you're performing the first song, right?
はい、このあとすぐに披露させていただきます！
Yes, we will perform it right after this!
はい、1曲目は鷹嶺ルイさんにアニメの主題歌でも話題でした「BOW AND ARROW」を披露していただきます！
Yes, the first song will be "BOW AND ARROW", which became a hot topic as an anime theme song, performed by Takane Lui!
はあー。あのフィギュアスケートの…
I see. That figure skating...
はい、今回は特にフィギュアスケート風のダンスを踊ってくださるダンサーさんと一緒にパフォーマンスさせていただきます！
Yes, this time we will perform together with dancers who will dance in a special figure-skating style!
うおおー、それは楽しみだなあ！
Whoa, I'm really looking forward to that!
そうですね。それではスタンバイの方よろしくお願いします！はい、よろしくお願いします！
That's right. Well then, please get ready for standby! Yes, please!
ね、あ、猫もっとくんと音瀬くんと…大神くん、あ、初登場だっけ？
Hey, Nekomata-kun, Otonose-kun, and... Ookami-kun, ah, is this your first appearance?
もう全然大丈夫ですよ！いけまーす！
I'm totally fine! Let's go!
そして2回目の登場が百鬼くん。はい、お久しぶりです。今回はアイスクリーム食べた？
And the second appearance is Nakiri-kun. Yes, long time no see. Did you eat ice cream this time?
ちょっと今日はまだ、まだ今日は食べてないです。
Well, I haven't eaten any yet today.
あ、そっかそっか。ま、あとでね、ゆっくりね、食べてね、いっぱい食べます。
Ah, I see, I see. Well, later on, slowly, eat lots later.
さて、スタンバイができたみたいですね。アニメをリスペクトしたダンスにもご注目ください。鷹嶺ルイで「BOW AND ARROW」！
Now, it seems the standby is ready. Please also pay attention to the dance respecting the anime. Takane Lui with "BOW AND ARROW"!
気が付けば靴は汚れ
If I realize it, my shoes are dirty
錆びついた諸刃を伝う雨
The rain runs down the rusted double-edged sword
憧れはそのままで
My admiration remains the same
夢から目覚めた先には夢
Beyond waking from a dream, there is another dream
聞こえたその泣き声
I heard that crying voice
消えている手前の咽ぶソワレ
The sobbing soiree just before it fades away
憧れのその先へ
To beyond that admiration
蠢く君を見つける為
To find you crouching
行け 行け 追いつけない速度で
Go, go, at a speed that cannot be caught
飛べ インパルス加速して
Fly, accelerate with impulse
行け 行け 追いつけない速度で
Go, go, at a speed you can't catch up to,
飛べ
fly,
インパルス加速して
accelerating with impulse.
行け きっとこの時を感じる為に 生まれてきたんだ
Go, surely you were born to feel this moment!
未来を掴んで
Grasping the future,
期待値を超えて
exceeding expectations,
額に吹き刺す風
the wind piercing our brows.
今に見なよ きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
Just you wait and see, surely everyone will notice your brilliance.
相応しい声で 視線追い越して 虚空を超えて行け
With a fitting voice, outstripping gazes, go beyond the void!
見遣っていく君の指から今 手を放す
Now letting go of your fingers as I look away.
気づけば謎は解け 木目ごと見慣れた板の上
Before I knew it, the mystery was solved, upon familiar wooden boards.
あの頃焦がれたような大人になれたかな
Have I become the kind of adult I yearned for back then?
そう君の苦悩は 君が自分で選んだ痛みだ
Yes, your anguish is the pain you chose yourself.
そして掴んだあの煌めきも 全て君のものだ
And all that glittering light you grasped belongs to you.
僕は弓になって 君の白んだ掌をとって強く引いた
I became the bow, taking your pale palm and pulling it tight.
今君は決して風に流れない 矢になって
Now you become an arrow that never drifts in the wind,
行け 行け 決して振り向かないで 飛べ もう届かない場所へ
go, go, never look back, fly to a place no longer reachable!
行け 行け 行け 君はいつだって輝いていた！
Go, go, go, you were always shining!
未来を掴んで
Grasping the future,
期待値を超えて
exceeding expectations,
額に吹き刺す風
the wind piercing our brows.
今に見なよ きっと君の眩しさに誰もが気づくだろう
Just you wait and see, surely everyone will notice your brilliance.
相応しい声で 視線追い越して 虚空を超えて行け
With a fitting voice, outstripping gazes, go beyond the void!
見遣っていく君の指から今 手を放す
Now letting go of your fingers as I look away.
はい、続いてはねこたかです。
Yes, next up is Neko-Taka.
よろしくお願いします。
We look forward to it.
ふたりはどういう関係なの？
What kind of relationship do you two have?
パーティ仲間で。
Party companions.
パーティ？
A party?
はい。
Yes.
よくルイの家で勝手にパーティ開催してまーす。
We often hold parties without permission at Lui's house.
勝手に！？
Without permission!?
まあ仲良しということでね。人の家で勝手にパーティはしないです、普通は。
Well, as close friends... Normally, you don't throw parties at someone else's house uninvited.
ねえ。
Right?
いやいや、そうなんですけど、最初は私もね、すごい驚いたんですが、
No, no, that's true, at first I was really surprised, but
最近ではね、もう私から「次いつパーティ？」っていうくらいにはね、取りこになっちゃってますね。
lately I've even become hooked to the point of asking, "When's the next party?"
これねこまた君の策謀かな？こうなると思ってました？
I wonder if this was Nekomata's scheme? Did you expect it to turn out like this?
こうなるとと思ってました。
I expected it to turn out this way.
ポルさんもう、今度どうですかパーティ？パーティっていうのは…
Polka-san, how about a party next time? A party is...
私も行っていいのかな？ぜひぜひ！
I wonder if I can go too? By all means, please!
やっぱりねこまた君が許可出すんだね。
So Nekomata-kun is the one giving permission after all.
楽しそうですね。
Sounds like fun.
ポルさんモモさんもぜひ！
Pol-san, Momo-san, please do!
おお、じゃあこの後でも行きましょうかポルさんねえ。
Oh, shall we go after this too, Pol-san?
ほらほら、鷹嶺くんが苦笑いしてますけど、勝手にネタ出されちゃいましたね。
See, Takane-kun is giving a wry smile, but her secrets were spilled without permission.
そんな二人にはですね、かっこ良さが詰まったダークチックな曲を披露していただきます！
For those two, they will perform a cool, dark-themed song!
身内知ってるじゃないか！
You know each other inside out!
そうなんですよ。
That's right.
でもねあのねこたかならではの帝王をも生かしたかっこいいパフォーマンスをしますので、楽しみにしていてください！
But you know, we'll give a cool performance unique to Neko-Taka that brings out our imperial flair, so please look forward to it!
はい、それではスタンバイお願いします！はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yes, then please get on standby! Yes, please!
いや、仲良さそうでいいですね。
Well, it's nice that they seem close.
まあぶっちゃけあれは鷹嶺くんも漫才でもなさそうだよね。
Well, frankly, even Takane-kun doesn't seem to be doing manzai.
そうですね。我々もパーティに混ざっていいみたいですから。なんか、あのルイさんの作るポテトサラダが絶品らしいのでね。
That's right. It seems we're allowed to join the party too. Apparently, Lui's homemade potato salad is exquisite.
なんか詳しいね。あーまあまあまあまあ！
You seem quite well-informed. Ah, well, well, well!
とりあえずスタンバイができたみたいですね。
Anyway, it seems they're ready on standby.
なんか拍手ごっこ？
Some kind of clapping game?
あ、いやいやいやいや、それでは参りましょう！ねこたかで「フィクサー」！
Ah, no, no, no, then let's go! "Fixer" by Neko-Taka!
今日までの記憶の全部を消してしまう時まで眠れない
I won't be able to sleep until the time I erase all memories up to today.
あしたから生きていく自分の身代わりが欲しくて堪らない
I can't help wanting a substitute for myself to live on starting tomorrow.
大丈夫と言わせて 後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
Let me say "It's all right" — won't you let me blame it on you later?
今更意味ないから
It's meaningless now,
後から君のせいにさせてはくれないか
won't you let me blame it on you later?
出来ない約束を
Unfulfillable promises
とうとうと溢れる 一言一言ばかりに 脳を奪われるくらい
overflowing endlessly, to the point where my brain
is stolen by every single word.
意味を成さない 何も出来ない
It makes no sense, I can do nothing.
見えない 逃げたい 飛びたい やめたい 逸らさない
Invisible, I want to flee, fly, stop, don't look away.
だから 沈め 沈め
So sink, sink,
這い上がれないほどまで 飽きるまで 落とせ 落とせ
until I can't crawl back up, until I'm sick of it—
drop them, drop them,
救い垂らす時まで
until the time salvation is trickled down.
嘘味の粒々を 喉から締め出した悲鳴ごと噛み砕く
Crunching up the grains of lies, along
with the screams squeezed from my throat.
笑顔が下手ばっかで 知ったような口ぶりに沿ってやり過ごす
My smiles are always clumsy, letting things
slide along with a knowing tone.
なりたかった
I didn't want to become this,
今日役立つ眠たい眠たい理想で救われることを待つ
waiting to be saved by sleepy,
sleepy ideals that are useful today.
一番目は「い」の口で言う
The first is said with an 'i' mouth,
力強く 固く 痛く 噛み締めて
biting down hard, painfully, with all my might.
死んでしまえ しまえ
Just die, just die.
この先も過去も知らず 嫌いなら 壊せ 壊せ
Knowing neither the future nor the past,
if you hate it, break it, break it.
どうせなら加害者になればいい
If you're going to, you might as well become the perpetrator.
食べきれない棘立ちも 何も生まれない悲しみも
The unchewable thorniness, the sorrow that births nothing—
味気なくて吐き出す前に もう次を歌え
before spitting them out as tasteless,
sing the next song already.
次を歌え
Sing the next song.
沈め 沈め
Sink, sink,
落とせ 落とせ
drop them, drop them.
どうせなら 踊り 踊れ
If you're going to, dance, dance,
灰色になり切る前に 打ち鳴らせ 変われ 変われ
ring out before turning entirely gray,
change, change,
眠り落ちる時まで
until the time I fall asleep.
どうせなら 奪え 奪え
If you're going to, take, take.
飼い慣らした嘘暴いて 煮え滾る頭に過った虚像を見ていた
Exposing the tamed lies, I was watching
the phantom that flashed through my boiling head,
自分を見ていた
I was watching myself.
続いてはルイなでのおふたりです。
Next up are the two of 'Luina-de'.
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you for having us!
元気がいいなぁ。
You guys have so much energy.
また言ってる。
There she goes again.
だってさ、先輩と後輩なんだよね。
Well, you're senpai and kohai, right?
はい、よくご飯に行ったりしてます。
Yes, we often go out to eat together.
ご飯？いいですね。
Eat? That's nice.
まあ、もっぱらしゃぶしゃぶですかね。
Well, mostly shabu-shabu, I suppose.
しゃぶしゃぶか。
Shabu-shabu, huh.
一緒の鍋をつつく関係、まあこれいいね。
Eating from the same pot—well, that's nice.
え、実は、え、かなでぽるさんに相談がありまして。
Actually, uh, Kanade has a consultation for Pol-san.
ポルさんに相談…？
A consultation for Pol-san...?
はい。
Yes.
ルイ先輩はいつまで経ってもね、私の「お母さん」にはなってくれないんですよ！
Lui-senpai won't become my 'mother'
no matter how much time passes!
ルイ先輩がお母さんにするの？
You want Lui-senpai to be your mother?
もちろん、もちろん！
Of course, of course!
カナデはいつでも優しいお母さんになって下さる方々を募集してます！よろしくお願いします！
Kanade is always recruiting kind mothers!
え、じゃあなんでお母さんになってあげないの？
Wait, why won't you be her mother, then?
逆に。
Reverse?
いやなんか、カナデは「娘」って感じがしないというか、娘になったらなんか手、手がかかりすぎてちょっと、責任が持てないなって感じなので、ちょっと親戚ポジションでいいかなって感じです。
Well, Kanade doesn't really feel like a 'daughter'... If she became
my daughter, it would be too much work, and I feel I couldn't
take responsibility, so a 'relative' position feels just right.
ああ、結構壮大だな。
Ah, that's quite grand.
音の声くんはじゃあ他にもママがいるの？
Otonase-kun, do you have other mammas too?
もちろん、もちろん！
Of course, of course!
じゃいらないでしょ。
Then you don't need one.
なんで怒るの？
Why are you mad?
え、それはね、頼れる人はいっぱいいたほうがいいじゃないですか。
Well, isn't it better to have lots of people you can rely on?
え、じゃあ、じゃあ逆にポルさん、かなでの「お父さん」になってくれませんか？
Then, Pol-san, won't you conversely
become Kanade's 'father'?
え？お父さん？
Eh? Father?
お父さん？
Father?
お父さん？え？お父さん？
Father? Eh? Father?
いや、その意見は父さんって言ってない！
Wait, I didn't say 'father' to that opinion!
ルイなでにはこのあと名前のない怪物をご披露していただきます！
Luina-de will now perform 'Namae no Nai Kaibutsu'!
え、なんでこの曲を選
Eh, why did you choose this song?
いや、もうすぐ、すぐ行けるんだ、そうやって。
Well, we can go right away like that.
いや私がですね、そのエゴイストが大好きで、その中でもこの曲がすごい大好きなんですけど、金デの初めての歌ってみたがこの曲で、
Well, I really love EGOIST, and among them, I really love this song, and Kanade's very first cover was this song,
いつか一緒に歌いたいなと思ってこの曲にしました。
so I chose it hoping we could sing it together someday.
えっ、うれしい！
Eh, I'm so happy!
え、それではですね、お二人ともスタンバイお願いします！
Well then, please standby, both of you!
はい、よろしくお願いします！
Yes, looking forward to it!
なんか、めちゃめちゃな子だね。
Man, what a wild one.
はい、ですね。なんかよく月曜日に現実を突きつけたりしてるみたいですよ。
Yeah, exactly. It seems she often shoves reality in people's faces on Mondays.
ああ、罪深い。
Ah, so sinful.
はい。クソガキだ。
Yes. Such a brat.
クソガキですね、はい。
A total brat, yeah.
まあしかし、歌で見せてくれるのでギャップ萌えしてる人も多いんじゃないかなと思います。
But since she shows us through her singing, I think many people find her gap moe appealing.
鷹嶺くんも歌うとカッコいいのに、なんかポンコツだからね。
Takane-kun looks so cool when singing, yet she's kind of clumsy.
そうですね。まあ、ギャップがある二人って感じじゃないでしょうかね。
That's true. Well, it's like two people with a gap, right?
はいじゃあ、それでは参りましょう。ルイナデで「名前のない怪物」。
Well then, let's go. "Namae no nai Kaibutsu" by Luinade.
御伽話は
The fairy tale
さっき死んだみたい
has died just now,
煉瓦の病棟でうまく歌えなくて
I couldn't sing well in this brick hospital.
霧に煙る夜 浮かべ赤い月
The foggy night, let the red moon float.
ほらみて 私を
Look at me,
目を逸らさないで
keep eyes on me.
黒い鉄格子の中で 私は生まれてきたんだ
Behind these iron bars, I was born.
悪意の代償を願え 望むがままにお前に
Pray for what deserves for your malice, and as you wish, to you
さあ与えよう正義を 壊して 壊される前に
I will bring justice, destroy them before they destroy us.
因果の代償を払い 共に行こう 名前のない怪物
We'll pay for our karma and go together, nameless monster.
耳鳴りがしてる
My ears are ringing.
鉄条網うるさくて
The barbed-wires are noisy.
思い出せないの あの日の旋律
I can't remember the melody on that day.
雨はまだやまない
Still rain has not stopped.
何にも見えないの
I can't see anything.
ほらみて こんなに大きくなったの
See, it has now grown this big.
黒い雨 降らせこの空 私は望まれないもの
Let the sky rain the black rain, I am an undesired being.
ひび割れたノイローゼ 愛す同罪の傍観者達に
A cracked neurotic, to beloved bystanders with the same guilt,
さあ今振るえ正義を 消せない傷を抱きしめて この身体を受け入れ
now exercise justice, embracing my unerasable scars, accepting this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
let's go together, nameless monster.
ああ 神は告げる 真の世界を
Ah, the god sentences the true world.
神の 世界を
The true world.
黒い鉄格子の中で
Behind these iron bars...
私は生まれてきたんだ
I was born
悪意の代償を願い
Praying for the compensation of malice,
望むがままにお前に
As much as you desire it,
さあ与えよう正義を
Now, I'll give you justice,
壊して 壊される前に
Break before you're broken,
因果の代償を払い
Paying the price of karma,
報いよ 名もなき怪物
Here's your retribution, nameless monster,
黒い雨 降らせこの空
Bring black rain to this sky,
私は望まれないもの
I am an unwanted entity,
ひび割れたノイローゼ
A cracking, fractured neurosis,
愛す同罪の傍観者達に
To the equally guilty onlookers I love,
さあ今振るえ正義を
Now, stir up that justice,
消せない傷を抱きしめて
Embracing wounds that cannot be erased,
この身体を受け入れ
Accepting this body,
共に行こう 名前のない怪物
Let's go together, nameless monster.
さてここからは、楠木ともりが鷹嶺ルイ生誕記念グッズをご紹介！
Now, let's introduce Takane Lui's birthday commemorative goods!
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド。キラキラなラメ入りアクリルスタンドが、とってもおしゃれな一品。
Glitter Acrylic Stand. A sparkling glitter acrylic stand that's a very stylish item.
光を浴びるたびに、きめ細かなラメがキラキラと輝きを放ちます。
Each time it catches the light, fine glitter radiates a dazzling shine.
光り輝くアクリルスタンドで、あなたの生活もさらに明るくなるでしょう。
With this glowing acrylic stand, your daily life will surely become even brighter.
ロック風パーカー。イベントやライブで着るだけでなく、日常にも溶け込むロック風パーカー。
Rock-style Hoodie. Not just for events or lives, but a rock-style hoodie that blends into everyday life.
前にジップがついているので、部屋着でも普段着でも使いやすい。ヘビロテ間違いなし！
With a front zipper, it's easy to use as loungewear or everyday wear. Bound to be your favorite!
ゆるかわバケットハット。つくねとつみれがワンポイントになっていて、シンプルおしゃかわ。
Cute & Casual Bucket Hat. Featuring Tsukune and Tsumire as cute, simple accents.
普段使いしやすいデザインで、手軽におしゃれ度UP。
With an easy-to-use design for everyday wear, easily boost your style.
カジュアル、ストリート、古着MIX、きれいめカジュアルの外しアイテムなど、幅広いスタイルにマッチ。
Matches a wide variety of styles, such as casual, street, vintage mix, or clean-casual accent pieces.
「え？」Tシャツ
"Eh?" T-shirt
ルイシュでおなじみのセリフ「え？」をモチーフにネタTとして堂々発売。
Proudly released as a joke T-shirt featuring Lui-shu's familiar catchphrase, "Eh?"
どんなコーディネートにも合う白で、夏は単体で、冬はパーカーと合わせてインナーとして、一年を通して使えます。
In versatile white to match any outfit, wear it alone in summer or as a hoodie inner layer in winter all year round.
全部セットは数量限定もアリ！
The complete set also has limited quantities available!
鷹嶺ルイ直筆サイン＆箔押し複製メッセージ入りポストカード特典
Bonus postcard with Takane Lui's handwritten signature & hot-stamped replica message.
hololive 公式ECサイトへ急げ！！
Rush to the official Hololive EC site!!
今だけ！！！ホロライブオフィシャルカードゲームPRカード1枚プレゼント！！！
Right now! Get 1 Hololive Official Card Game PR card with every complete set purchase!
続いてはミオルイでーす。
Next up is MioLui!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please treat us well!
なんかこの、この2人って珍しいよね。
It's kind of rare to see these two together, huh?
そうですね。お、結構ね、お話はしたり仲いいんですよ。
That's right. We actually talk quite a bit and get along well.
うん、何について話してるの？
Yeah, what do you guys talk about?
えーっと、主に、私がそもそもミオ社の歌が本当に大好きで
Umm, mainly, I've always just loved Miosha's singing so much,
よく歌のお話をしたりとか、あとは個人的に私の悩みを聞いてもらったりとかしてまーす。
We often talk about singing, and she also listens to my personal worries and stuff.
頼りになるからね。
She's so reliable, after all.
その、なんか特別なエピソードとかあったりする？
Do you have any special episodes or anything?
特別なエピソードって言うと、私がちょっとショボーンとした時があったんですけど、その時にパーティを開いてくれまして
As for a special episode, when I was feeling a bit down once, she actually threw a party for me—
その時にミオ社が花束をプレゼントしてくれたんですよ。覚えてる？
And Miosha presented me with a bouquet of flowers. Do you remember?
覚えてる覚えてる！ルイの色のね、花束をね。ルイからのね、あの花束をプレゼントしてくれて、それが紙袋も…
I remember, I remember! A bouquet in Rui's color. The bouquet from Rui, and it even had a paper bag...
そう紙袋も！それがすっごく綺麗で曇ってた心が一瞬にして晴れましたね。
Yeah, even the paper bag! It was so gorgeous, and my clouded heart cleared up in an instant.
素敵だね。
That's wonderful.
大神さんはよく花とか買うの？
Does Ookami-san often buy flowers?
あ、はい！あの、お花すごい大好きで、あの、うちも落ち込んだときとかね、あの、お花を買うとき結構あるんですけど
Ah, yes! Um, I love flowers so much. When I'm feeling down, I quite often buy flowers, but—
猫が食べちゃうんでね、あんまり買えないんですけどね。
Cats eat them, so I can't buy them very often, you know.
あーそうですね、猫ね。
Ah, that's right, cats.
さっき聞き逃してしてたけど、君たちもよくパーティするんだね。
I missed it earlier, but you guys also throw parties often, huh?
あ、そうですね。まあでも、お粥とと同じパーティですね。
Ah, that's right. Well, but it's the same party as Okayu's.
そうですね、あの私もよく実を参加させていただいております。
That's right, um, I actually often get to participate as well.
え、さっき隠してたのって、白上さんも参加してるってこと？
Eh, what you were hiding earlier—does that mean Shirakami-san participates too?
あ、あ、そうですね、あの、ミオさんのオムライスとルイさんのポテトサラダもう本当にめちゃめちゃ絶品なんですよ。
Ah, ah, that's right. Um, Mio-san's omurice and Rui-san's potato salad are honestly just absolute masterpieces.
いや、ちょっと収集つかなくなれそうなので、スタンバイお願いします！
Man, this is getting a bit out of hand, so please standby!
はーい！よろしくお願いします。
Okay! Please take care of us.
ナーなんかつくったりしてるの? パーティーで。
Are you making something? For the party?
いや私あの食べる専門ですね。食べる専門。
No, I'm just a specialist in eating. Eating specialist.
甘やかされてるね。
You're being pampered.
そうですね。
That's right.
ポルさんも一度いかがですか?
How about you once, Pol-san?
ポルさんも甘えていいってこと?
So Pol-san can just be pampered too?
それはちょっと
That's a bit...
それではまいりましょう。
Well then, let's get started.
みおるいでビートイーター!
Mio and Lui with "Beat Eater"!
気付いたんだ今はrollin'
I realized now we're rollin'
止まりたくないんだno need
I don't want to stop, no need
分かってんだ魅せられたからって
I know it's because I was fascinated,
雑な罠に嵌るつもりなど無い
I have no intention of falling into clumsy traps.
当たり前が止まんない怖いな
It's scary how normality won't stop,
もどかしさも正しい命題
Frustration is also a valid proposition.
ハロー 湧いてくる束の間の自負心
Hello, the fleeting pride welling up,
そこからはどう見えてる?
How does it look from there?
tell me, tell me
どれだけ僕を救ってくれるの
How much can you save me?
反響していく声 加速して
Echoing voices, accelerating,
始まりは何処から?
Where did it all begin?
それも容赦無い力
That's also a merciless power,
身体を支配している満ち足りた意欲
Desires overflowing, dominating the body.
タフに噛んでいくスタイル
A style biting through toughly,
まにまに幕を上げるのさ
Raising the curtain at will.
何がどうたって不思議じゃない
No matter what happens, it's not strange,
振りが増し答えになって響き出すよ
Amplifying movements, echoing as an answer.
消えていかない感覚
A sensation that won't fade away,
あくまで踊ってたいだけ
I just want to keep dancing.
気付いたんだ今はrollin'
I realized now we're rollin'
止まりたくないんだno need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばい何となくなのに
Even though it somehow feels dangerous,
見透かされてんの鬼
I'm being seen right through.
予想よりうねって長い傾向 不確かなものに包まれてんだね
A tendency winding longer than expected, surrounded by uncertain things.
そこらじゅうに転がってる惰弱
Weakness rolling around everywhere,
妄想だって思いのほか重要
Even delusions are more important than you'd think.
心に逆らった外れた振る舞い
Behavior straying against the heart,
早まったのさ引くに引けない様相
Hastened, a situation where I can't back down.
ほら手に入れた座標を打ち込め
Look, input the coordinates you obtained,
姿を映してアブラカダブラ
Reflecting your figure, abracadabra.
道は分かれてたんだ
The paths had split,
それも遠い所から
Even from far away,
全て間違いじゃない悲しみ方
A way of grieving where nothing is wrong.
満更でもない
It's not half bad,
まにまに塗り直すのさ
Repainting it at will.
今になればいつだって構わない
Whenever it is now, I don't care,
色を変え答えになって溢れ出すよ
Changing colors, overflowing as an answer.
消えていかない感覚
A sensation that won't fade away,
まだまだ足りないみたい
It seems like it's still not enough.
重なり合う光 痛みに寄り添う
Overlapping lights, nestling close to the pain,
何処にも消えないで欲しい
I want it never to fade anywhere.
留まる濃い深い重心頼り
Depending on the lingering, deep, heavy center of gravity,
傷付くこともある
There are times when I get hurt.
タフに噛んでいくスタイル まにまに体現するのさ
A style biting through toughly, embodying it at will.
何がどうたって不思議じゃない
No matter what happens, it's not strange,
振りが増し答えになって響き出すよ
Amplifying movements, echoing as an answer.
消えていかない感覚
A sensation that won't fade away,
あくまで踊ってたいだけ
I just want to keep dancing.
気付いたんだ今はrollin'
I realized now we're rollin'
止まりたくないんだno need
I don't want to stop, no need
やばい何となくなのに
Even though it somehow feels dangerous,
見透かされてんの鬼
I'm being seen right through.
続いては鷹嶺ルイで。
Next is Takane Lui.
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Yes, nice to work with you.
よろしくお願いします!
Nice to work with you!
鷹嶺くんはなんか、うーん、最近ハマってるゲームとかあるの?
Takane-kun, do you have any games you're into lately?
ハマってるゲームあります。あの、最近ってわけでもないんですけど、事務所に入ってからドラゴンクエストというゲームに出会いまして。
I have games I'm into. Well, not necessarily just recently, but ever since joining the agency, I discovered a game called Dragon Quest.
ああ! ドラゴンクエスト! おおー!
Ah! Dragon Quest! Ohh!
ナンバリング1から11までやっていて、派生とかもあるので、本当に面白くてですね、大好きです。
I've played numbering 1 through 11, and since there are spin-offs too, it's really interesting and I love it.
あとさ、ドラクエの、どんなところが魅力?
And also, what makes DQ so charming?
魅力たくさんあるんですけど、本当に人生の教科書だなと思うことが結構多くて。
There are many charms, but I often feel like it's truly a textbook for life.
もちろん悲しいこともあるんですけど、それを仲間たちと支え合って前に進んでいくパワーと、
Of course there are sad things too, but the power to support each other with comrades and move forward,
ナンバリングが進んでいくにつれて分かる真実とかがあったりとか、
and truths that become clear as the numbering progresses,
長年愛されてる理由が詰まってるなって感じますね。
makes you feel like the reasons it's been loved for years are packed in there.
はい。じゃあ、ゲーム以外の
Yes. So, besides games...
なんかドラクエのそういうイベントとか行ったりしてるの？
Do you ever go to Dragon Quest events and stuff?
はい、行ってますね。
Yeah, I do.
ドラクエのテーマパークだったりとか、
Dragon Quest theme parks,
あとは限定ショップに行ったりとか、
or limited-time shops,
あとアニメもあるので、あの、ファンの人と同時視聴とかしたりしてましたね。はい。
and since there's an anime, um, I've done watch-alongs with fans. Yeah.
充実してんね！
You're living it up!
はい、充実してます。
Yeah, I am.
そんなドラクエ大好きな高根ルイさんには、
For Takane Lui, who loves Dragon Quest so much,
これからアニメ「ドラゴンクエスト ダイの大冒険」の初代オープニング「生きるをする」を披露していただきます！
she will now perform the first opening theme of the anime Dragon Quest: The Adventure of Dai, "Ikiru wo Suru"!
はい！
Yes!
それは楽しみだ。
That's something to look forward to.
特別なおしゃれにも注目してくれると嬉しいです。はい。
I'd be happy if you also pay attention to my special outfit. Yes.
それではスタンバイお願いします！
Then please standby!
はい、よろしくお願いします！お願いします！
Yes, thank you! Thank you!
いや、はまるものがあるっていうのは、いいよね。
Man, having something you're really into is great.
いいですよねー！
It really is!
何やらこの曲を歌ってほしいっていうリクエストもかなり多かったみたいですよ。
Apparently, there were quite a lot of requests to sing this song.
おっ、てことはみんな待望ってわけだね。
Oh, so everyone's been waiting for it, huh?
ですねー！
Indeed!
それではスタンバイができたみたいなので行きましょう！高根ルイさんで『生きるをする』です。どうぞ！
Well then, it looks like she's ready, so let's go! Takane Lui with "Ikiru wo Suru". Here we go!
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Loving myself all the way through,
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, can I still believe in it?
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where this journey leads,
生きるをする
living life.
あれ、いつからだ？本音が弱音になったな
Huh, since when did my true feelings become mere complaints?
逃げないことが強さになったんだ
Not running away became my strength,
なあ、見つからない？自信じゃなく自分自身
Hey, can't you find it? Not confidence, but your very self.
きっとなまだ探せてない忘れものがあるはず
Surely there's still something forgotten I haven't found yet,
ずっとまだ伝えてない伝えたい言葉
words I've always wanted to convey but haven't yet.
見ててくれるなら魅せてみせるのに
If you'll watch, I'll show you.
僕が僕を愛し抜くこと
Loving myself all the way through,
なあ、まだ信じてもいいか？
Hey, can I still believe in it?
くすぶるのは、ちゃんと燃えたからだ
Smoldering means it burned properly,
どこへ向かう旅だとしても
No matter where this journey leads,
ただ、目を見開いて夢を見る
just opening my eyes wide and dreaming,
夢を知る
knowing dreams.
よう、生きてるかい？
Yo, are you alive?
本当の強さ きみだけが分かっていればいいのさ
True strength is fine as long as only you understand it.
逃げたり傷ついた数だけ居場所は増えたりする
The places you belong increase by the times you've run or been hurt.
見ててくれ 姿じゃなく生き方を
Watch not my appearance, but my way of living.
僕が僕を愛し抜かなきゃ
If I don't love myself all the way through,
終わらない聖者の交信、悲しみの
endless communion of saints, to the seams
縫い目に投げキス
of sorrow, blowing a kiss.
どこへ向かう旅でも行こうぜ
Let's go on any journey we head toward,
まだ手を取り合って
still holding hands together.
脳、映像、スカイはグレー、夜を駆ける
Brain, images, the sky is gray, running through the night.
束の間、終幕、裏切りは愛のおまけ
A fleeting moment, the finale, betrayal is love's bonus.
かさぶたになる日々 美しくはないのさ
Days that turn into scabs aren't beautiful,
腰に巻いた正義の切れ味はどんなだ
how sharp is the sword of justice worn at your waist?
僕らは違う痛みを生きる
We live through different pains.
勇敢でいたい、立ち向かいたい
I want to be brave, I want to face it,
眠っていたストーリーを凄いスピードで覚ましたいんだ
I want to wake up the sleeping story with incredible speed.
僕が僕を愛せる強さを
The strength to love myself,
かなり愛してもいいか？
can I love myself quite a bit?
くすぶるのは、燃えかすになるまで
Smoldering until it becomes ashes,
どこへ向かう旅だっていいさ いいのさ
any journey we head toward is fine, it's fine.
ただ、目を見開いて息をする
Just opening my eyes wide and breathing.
生きるをする
Living life.
続いてはおにがんです。
Next is "Onikan."
よろしくお願いします！おにがん！
Please look forward to it! Onikan!
前回に引き続いてもう二人は仲がいいね？
Just like last time, you two get along really well, huh?
はい！
Yeah!
仲いいですよ
We get along well.
息もぴったりだ
You guys are totally in sync.
はい
Yeah.
なきりさんは今日アイスクリーム食べた？
Nakiri-san, did you eat ice cream today?
今日はね、まだ食べてないんですよ。でもお弁当食べました。
Today, I haven't eaten any yet. But I ate a bento box.
ああ！
Ah!
お弁当ね、おいしいの入ったからね。
The bento had delicious stuff in it.
おいしかったです。
It was delicious.
はい、私たちもあとで食べましょうね、ポルさんね。
Yeah, let's eat some later too, Pol-san.
そうだね。
That's right.
おなかぺっこぺこだからね。
We're super starving, after all.
そうだね。
That's right.
そして何やらお二人は私たちMCに聞きたいことがあるらしいですよ。
And apparently, the two of you have something you want to ask us MCs.
はい。
Yes.
なになに？
What, what?
いや、こうやってミュージックガーデンやってますけど、お二人はなんか歌いたいってなってないですか？
Well, we're doing Music Garden like this, but don't you two feel like singing?
歌いたい！みたいな。
Like "I want to sing!"
え？歌いたい？
Huh? Want to sing?
歌いたい歌いたい。
Want to sing, want to sing.
まあ、多少ね。
Well, somewhat, yeah.
唇噛んだり、体動かしたりするけどね。
We bite our lips or move our bodies, but...
MCだからね。
Because we're MCs.
ねえ、はい、MCなので。
Right, yeah, since we're MCs.
じゃあ、こう歌って踊りたいって言ってもいいすか？
So, is it okay to say we want to sing and dance like this?
いや、みなさんのいいパフォーマンス見てたらね。
Well, seeing everyone's great performances...
おお。じゃあ！
Oh. Then!
じゃあね、ねえ、踊って歌いましょうか。
Then, hey, shall we dance and sing?
はい、じゃあ立っていただいて、あ、私もう、あの、皆さん立っていただいて、いいですか？
Yes, then please stand up—ah, me too, um, everyone please stand up, is that okay?
あっち側で、あの、衣装を着替えていただいて、いいですか？
Over there, um, could you go change your outfits?
はい！じゃあすぐ行く、すぐ行く、すぐ行って！
Okay! Then go right away, go right away, go right away!
いっってきまーす！
We're off!
じゃスタンバイしに行ってください！
Go get ready, please!
はい！じゃあね、こちらでいったんCMです。
Okay! Then, here's a brief commercial break.
あ、それ私のセリフ！
Hey, that's my line!
おい、準備できたかな？大丈夫かな？
Hey, is preparation done? Are you okay?
あ、まだのなこうあったんで着替えましたけども。
Ah, there was still some inside so we changed, but...
あ、できた？
Ah, you're done?
じゃあね、私たちも行きましょうか。
Then, shall we go too?
行きましょう行きましょう！
Let's go, let's go!
はい、じゃあポルさんカンペ呼んでください。
Yes, then Pol-san, please read the cue card.
え？え？
Huh? Eh?
それでは聞いてください。おにがん＋ふぶぽるでチャンカパーナ！
Then please listen to it. "Onikan + Fubupor" with "Chankapana"!
深夜バスで君を見た 息を呑むような黒髪
I saw you on the midnight bus, the black hair took my breath away
行き先は違うけれど オレは迷わず飛び乗る
The direction was wrong but I got on without hesitation
一人じゃ悲しすぎる夜さ 誰かと話したかった
The night is too sad when I'm alone, I wanted to talk to someone
君もうれしそうで どちらからともなく 手を握る
You look happy, I don't know who started first, we hold hands
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby chan chan chankapana chankapana
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so much it hurts
もう ジン ジン 燃えている 身体は止まらない
I'm burning here, I can't stop my body
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby chan chan chankapana chankapana
頷いた君 抱きしめた
You nodded and I held you
恥らうその瞳 狂ってしまいそう
The way you look shy, I'm going crazy
夜の吐息の中 チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
In the night's sigh, chankapana chankapana
チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Chankapana chankapana
バスを捨てて二人は 眠れる場所を探した
Leaving the bus behind, we looked for a place to stay
うやうやしく服を脱ぎ ベッドに滑り込む花
Respectfully taking off clothes, your skin slips into the bed
この世にも天使がいたのさ その肌に触れたんだ
So there were angels in this world, I touched that skin
「恋って好き」なんて悪戯に言うから 舞い上がる
"I like love" Because you say it teasingly, we fly high
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby chan chan chankapana chankapana
人生で一番美味しいもの
The most delicious thing in my life
そう ナン ナン 何だって 抱いていたいい
Yes, I want to hold you tight again and again
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby chan chan chankapana chankapana
まだまだ君が足りないよ
I'm still not satisfied with you
露なその果実 狂ってしまいそう
That exposed fruit, I'm going crazy
夜よ覚めないでくれ チャンカパーナ
Don't let this night end, chankapana
チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Chankapana chankapana
美しい恋にするよ
I'll make it a beautiful love
約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
I promise you, chankapana
美しい恋にするから、約束するよ、チャンカパーナ
I promise to make this a beautiful love, Chankapana.
月がふたりを探すから
The moon is searching for the two of us,
今夜 世界から身を隠そう
so tonight let's hide away from the world.
覗いたその肌は 褐色(かしょく)の葡萄(ぶどう)だね
That skin you peeked at is like a golden chardonnay.
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, chan-chan-chankapaana, chankapaana,
痛いほど君が欲しいよ
I want you so much it hurts.
もう ジン ジン 燃えている 身体は止まらない
Burning, jin-jin, heated up, my body won't stop.
Baby チャンチャンチャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Baby, chan-chan-chankapaana, chankapaana,
オレの腕にしがみついた
clinging tightly to my arms.
ゃしゃなその肩に 狂ってしまいそう
I'm going crazy over those delicate shoulders.
夜の吐息の中 チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Amidst the sighs of the night, chankapaana, chankapaana...
チャンカパーナ チャンカパーナ
Chankapaana, chankapaana...
Win seralala love secure la la kimi e win
Win, seralala love, secure la la, to you...
seralala yamakkakaba o
Win, seralala...
高嶺ルイ生誕3Dライブを見ている諸君 お初にお目にかかる
Spectators watching Takane Lui's birthday 3D live, I make my first appearance before you.
私はゼロ 黒の騎士団の総帥にして 世界への反逆者
I am Zero, Supreme Commander of the Black Knights, and a rebel against the world.
ここまでのM話ではどうだったかな? 大いに盛り上がったことだろう
How was the M talk up until now? It must have been quite exciting.
ほう だがまだ足りないな 諸君らならまだまだ盛り上がれるはずだ 高嶺ルイの歌によってな
Oh? But that's still not enough. You should be able to get much more excited, through Takane Lui's songs.
ヌルースビブリタニアが命じる 高嶺ルイよ コードギアス的主題歌メドレーで
Britannia the master commands you, Takane Lui, with a Code Geass theme song medley...
さらに盛り上げるのだ!
to get them even more fired up!
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな 瞬間は
The moment that feels like it could change myself and even the world...
いつもすぐそばに…
is always right by my side...
隠せぬ苛立ちと 立ち尽くす自分を見つめ
Gazing at myself standing still with frustration I can't hide,
立ち尽くす自分を
standing still myself...
迷いながら 悩みながら 悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
while lost, troubled, and regretful, I just need to decide.
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ 戸惑いは消え去り
The single word you gave me chases away all confusion.
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Light shone into my empty room.
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
The vast sky I looked up at is turning a pure, clear blue.
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を 決めた
I decided to open the window I had closed.
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな 瞬間は
The moment that feels like it could change myself and even the world...
いつもすぐそばに…
is always right by my side...
夢見てた、夢 果て無き遠く
The dream I dreamed, endlessly far away.
乾いた日々の 空色・手の中
The sky blue of those dry days in my hands.
The sky-blue of dry days, in my hands
等間隔 音の中で試行錯誤
Trial and error amidst evenly spaced sounds,
時間・間隔の無い空間 ah
In a space without time or intervals, ah.
等身大 音をたてて
Making life-sized sounds,
僕の顔、造って行く
I construct my face.
キレイに、片方だけ。
Beautifully, but only on one side.
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと叫べ
Roar "O lion, O tiger!" on the beast's trail,
茜さす空の 彼方にまほろば
My spiritual home lies beyond the glowing sky.
幽囚の孤独に 彷徨う青春は
Youth wandering in the solitude of imprisonment,
弱さと怒りが 姿無き敵ですか
Are weakness and rage formless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は 己を知りがたし
Father, I still find myself hard to understand.
先立つ兄らの 見えない背中を追えば
Chasing the unseen backs of the brothers before me,
迷いの夜に 明星は誘う
The morning star beckons on a night of straying.
死して終わらぬ 夢を焦がれても
Even yearning for dreams that don't end in death,
確かな君こそ我が命
You, my certainty, are my very life.
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Living like a butterfly and flower in gale-force wilds,
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
An illusion blooming alongside eternal spring.
混濁の純潔 この身は汚れても
Even if this body and purity are muddied,
心の錦を 信じていてください
Please believe in the brocade of my heart.
母よ 決して我は 涙を見せねども
Mother, even though I will never show my tears,
足下の草に 露は消えもせず
The dew on the grass beneath won't vanish.
世界が朽ち果てても 変ることのないものがある
Even if the world rots away, some things never change.
涙をこらえてでも 守るべきものが僕らにはある
Even holding back tears, there are things we must protect.
何万年億年前からのメッセージが 体内でうずだき 鳴り響く
Messages from eons ago churn and echo within my body.
しがれた声で 明日を呼ぶ 傷だらけの手で 君守る
With a raspy voice calling tomorrow, with scarred hands, I protect you.
I continue to fight
見つめ合い 手と手を重ねて ガラス越しのキミとボク
Staring at each other, hands overlapping, you and I through the glass.
こんなにも側にいるのに
Even though we're so close by,
暗い闇を白に染めるよ
I'll dye the dark gloom in white.
出口のない 君のもとへ
Toward you, who have no exit,
運命を切り裂く流れ星
A shooting star tearing through fate.
あふれる君の涙 ボクがいま奪い去る
I will now take away your overflowing tears.
モザイクカケラ ひとつひとつ繋ぎ合わせて描いてゆく
Connecting mosaic pieces one by one to draw it out.
あなたがくれた 出逢いと別れも
Even the encounters and partings you gave me.
こんなはずじゃない そう思って眠り
Thinking "It shouldn't be like this," I fall asleep.
目覚めればいつもの 変わらない空回り
Waking up to the same unchanging, fruitless spinning.
意味も無く繰り返し
Repeating it all meaninglessly.
モザイクカケラ 拾い集めた「上手く生きる為の術」
Gathering mosaic pieces: 'the art of living well'.
歪なソレが美しく見えたんだ
That warped thing looked so beautiful to me.
強がりながら つまづきながら選び抜いた道の上で
On the path I chose while bluffing and stumbling,
剥がれ落ちては 埋まらないカケラ
Pieces that peel off and cannot be refilled.
剥がれ落ちては　埋まらないカケラ
...and from the deepest cut, a fluid runs
...
...let's call it "love."
はい、ということで特報PV見ていただきましたけれども、
Hai! So, you've just seen the special PV...
なんと、この鷹嶺ルイ、なんと、なんとコードギアスアンバサダーに決定しました！やったー！嬉しい！ありがとうございます！
...and Code Geass Ambassador! Yay, I'm so happy! Thank you so much!
もうめちゃくちゃね、コードギアスシリーズ大、大、大好きなので、
I love the Code Geass series so much, so...
こんな素晴らしい機会をいただけるの本当に嬉しいでございます。皆さんのおかげです。本当にありがとうございます。
...to be given such a wonderful opportunity is truly wonderful. Thank you all so much.
そしてですね、皆さんお気づき、もうもう気づいてますよね？
And you know what, you've probably already noticed...
もうなんと、ルルーシュ役の福山さんが鷹嶺ルイと呼んでいただき、演じていただきました！本当によりすごい！こんな豪華なことってあるんですか？いや、本当にありがとうございます。
...Fukuyama-san, who plays Lelouch, called me "Takane Lui" and made the announcement for me! That's incredible! Can you believe something so gorgeous could happen? I'm so grateful.
もうコードギアスメダルでもね、あのバッグに
And since Code Geass medals... wait, the back...
はい、あのコードギアスのアニメーションもエンディングと歴代のエンディングとオープニングも流れたということで本当に豪華な仕上がりになっていたんですけれど
...even the Code Geass animation openings and endings from the past were played, so it turned out so gorgeous!
いかがでしたか、皆さん？
How did you like it, everyone?
アンバサダーとしてのお仕事はですね、歌ってみたを上げたりとか、あとは同時視聴をしたりとか、あとはそのほか色々、色、もりだくさんで用意しておりますので、詳細はですね、このあとコードギアスシリーズの公式YouTubeチャンネルにも投稿されますので、ぜひぜひチェックしてみてください。
As an ambassador, my work will include singing covers, co-streaming, and preparing lots of other fun things, so details will be posted on the official Code Geass YouTube channel later, so please check it out!
もちろん、私のXでも、XやYouTubeチャンネルでも、詳細をその都度お伝えしていきますので、チャンネル登録、そしてXのフォローもよろしくお願いします。
Of course, on my X and YouTube channel, I'll share details as they come, so please follow my channel and X!
さて、このあとはですね、新曲を披露させていただきます。よっ。
Now, after this, I'll be revealing a new song! Yay!
来ましたよ、私の新曲が。
It's finally here, my new song.
ということで新曲のタイトルはですね、「ジグザグ」という曲になっております。
So the title of the new song is "ZIG-ZAG."
ジグザグというのはトラウマの別称になっているんですけれども、
"ZIG-ZAG" refers to the scars of trauma...
そのジグザグ、自分のなかにあるトラウマと戦って、前を向いていこうというかっこいい、かっこよく前を向いていくという曲になっておりますので、
...and it's a cool song about fighting those inner traumas and moving forward coolly.
ぜひぜひみんなにもちょっと聞いていただいて、「あ、こんなことあるな、私もこんなことあるな」と共感していただけたら嬉しいなと思います。
So I hope everyone can listen to it and relate, thinking, "Oh, I've experienced that too." I'd be so happy.
それではじゃあ曲フリは、コードギアスのアンバサダーにもなったということで、久しぶりにルルーシュ流で行きたいと思います！みんな、準備はいいか？
And since I've become the ambassador for Code Geass, for the song intro, I want to do it in Lelouch's style! Are you ready, everyone?
あ、私の準備もいいか、大丈夫か？
Is my preparation ready too? Am I okay?
それではいきますよ。
Alright, here we go!
ルルーシュび、鷹嶺ルイが命ずる。
Lelouch style: Takane Lui's commands are absolute.
お前たち、新曲を聞け！
You subjects, listen to the new song!
ワン・ツー・スリー・フォー
One, two, three, four!
「幸せ？」って呟いた問いがラッタラッタッタ
Asking "Are you happy?" with a rat-a-tat-tat,
こびり付いて離れんわ　ダメだラッタラッタッタ
stuck and refusing to leave, no good, rat-a-tat-tat.
無味無臭の生活が思い出せないや
I can't even remember a bland, tasteless life,
忘れたいから歌った　馬鹿だラッタラッタッタ
singing because I want to forget, how foolish, rat-a-tat-tat.
恨む事も憎む事も賢くない故　出来なかった
I wasn't smart enough to either resent or hold a grudge, so I couldn't.
これが君の結末ならば笑ってしまいたいほど　嘘　嘘　嘘　「嘘つき」
If this is your ending, I'd laugh out loud—lie, lie, lie, "liar."
やだ　痛い痛い痛い痛いな　奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No way, it hurts, hurts, hurts, wishing just a bit for a miracle or something,
もう嫌嫌嫌嫌嫌！　タチが悪いわ
I've had enough, enough, enough—what a bad attitude.
ねえ　辛い Lie Lie Lie 否？　おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, painful, Lie, Lie, Lie, right? Rip out all the weirdness,
薄情で結構　好きに呼んでいいよ
call it shallow, call it whatever you like,
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです　で・で・で・で・す
I want to say bye-bye to my trauma—de-de-de-de!
私、甘え上手になれなかった 可愛いこととか足りなかった
I couldn't learn how to depend on others, I lacked cuteness and all that.
後悔が煩い夜だ
It's a night noisy with regret.
過去は過去だと割り切れちゃえば?
If I could just write off the past as the past,
きっとイイコトあるさ とか
surely there'd be good things, or so they say.
それくらい百も承知だ ラッタッタ
I know that much hundredfold, rattatta.
願う事も 祈る事も 許されないから黒く染めた
Prayers and wishes aren't allowed, so I dyed it all black.
元の色も思い出せない 絡んだ運命の糸 糸 糸 糸
I can't even remember the original color, tangled threads of fate...
やだ 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 悲劇のヒロイン気取っちゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, acting like some tragic heroine,
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌! 諦めいちゃえば?
Just no, no, no, no, no! Why don't I just give up?
でも 会いたい たい たいな 思考回路がこんががって
But I want to see you so badly, my thought process is all tangled up,
明日またきっと 壊すけどいいの
Tomorrow I'll surely break it again, but is that okay?
トラウマさえ愛おしいのです です です です
Even trauma is dear to me, desu, desu, desu, desu.
夢の中で君と 手を繋いでいるの
In my dreams, I'm holding hands with you,
何も知らない あの頃の二人のままで
just like the two of us back then, knowing nothing.
でも わかっているよ すぐに覚めてしまうと
But I know it'll fade away the moment I wake up,
それならばいっそ 君の手でそっと 止め刺して ほら 今 今 今!
so if that's the case, gently finish me off with your own hands, right now, now, now!
やだ 痛い 痛い 痛い 痛いな 奇跡とかちょっと望んじゃって
No, it hurts, hurts, hurts, hoping a little for some miracle,
もう 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌 嫌! タチが悪いわ
Just no, no, no, no, no! I've got such a bad disposition.
ねぇ 辛い lie lie lie 否? おかしいとこ全部えぐり取って
Hey, painful, lie lie lie, no? Gouging out all the messed up parts,
薄情で結構 好きに呼んでいいよ
Call me coldhearted all you like, go ahead.
トラウマにバイバイしたいのです です です です です です です です
I want to say bye-bye to trauma, desu, desu, desu...
「嘘っ」
"No way..."
楽しくお届けしてきましたミュジックガーデン あっという間にエンディングの時間となりました。ぽるか今日はどうでしたか?
We've brought you a fun time at Music Garden! Before you know it, it's time for the ending. Polka, how was today?
いやー なんか今日は私も一緒に歌って踊っちゃったからね いつも以上にボルテージが上がっちゃったね ああ
Man, since I was singing and dancing along today too, my voltage went up even more than usual! Ah...
いつも以上にボルテージが上がっちゃったね ああ あと もう1時間
Even more than usual! And also, another hour...
やらないですけど、もっとやりたいんですけどね! グッズ販売とプレミア公開もありますので ああそうかそうか
We're not doing that, but I want to do more! There's also merchandise sales and the premiere screening, so— Ah, is that right?
いや、たかねく、今日は天気もりだねえ まさか
Man, Takaneku, today was jam-packed with weather... wait, of all times, this is...
ためてるためてる 私もね早く言いたくて言いたくてたまらなかったです このあとグッズ販売と新曲プレミア公開そしてメンバーシップ限定配信もありますので楽しんでいただけたら嬉しいです
Saving it, saving it! I was dying to announce it myself too. There will be merch sales, the new song premiere, and a membership-only stream afterwards, so I hope you enjoy them!
本当にこのあとももりだくさんだ 改めてお誕生日おめでとうね ありがとうございます ミュージックガーデン2できて本当に嬉しいです ぽるさんもふぶさんも本当にありがとうございました
Really, there's so much more after this! Happy birthday once again. Thank you so much, I'm so happy we could make Music Garden 2. Thank you so much, Polka-san and Fubuki-san.
是非ね またまたやりたいね まあ是非またやりたいですね せっかくですのでゲストの皆さんにも感想をいただきましょう
By all means, we'd love to do it again! Well, we definitely want to do it again. Since we have the chance, let's hear impressions from our guests as well!
皆さんから何か言いたいことがあるみたいですよ おっ
It looks like everyone has something they want to say. Oh!
るい！ お誕生日おめでとう！
Lui! Happy birthday!
ありがとうございます みんなと歌えて幸せでした またコラボしようね
Thank you so much! It was blissful singing with everyone. Let's collab again!
はいでは本当にあっという間ですが今夜のミュージックガーデンはここまでとなります。ありがとうございました！
Right then, though it went by in a flash, tonight's Music Garden comes to an end here. Thank you very much!
それではまたミュージックガーデン3が叶う日まで、さようなら！
Until the day Music Garden 3 becomes a reality, goodbye!
ラプやべえぞ
Laplus, this is bad!
どうしたの
What's wrong?
とんでもねえグッズ出るぞ
Some crazy merch is coming out!
はい？
Huh?
バカすげえグッズが一挙に来るぞ
A ton of insanely awesome merch is dropping all at once!
Tシャツ！
T-shirts!
ラメ入りアクリルスタンド！
Glitter acrylic stands!
ゆるカーバケットハット！
Yuruka bucket hat!
ほしい！
I want it!
ロック風パーカー！
Rock-style hoodie!
買いたい！
I want to buy it!
そして
And...
は？
Huh?
すっごい！
Awesome!
隙間付きポストカードがつくぞ！
It comes with a gap postcard!
なんだってー！？
What?!
さらにホロカもついてくる！
It even comes with a Holocard!
うおー！
Woah!
これは買いでしょ！
This is a must-buy!